Support for NPR Music comes from Capital
One, proud supporters of NPR Music and
the Tiny Desk Contest. What's in your
wallet? Learn more at capitalone.com.
>> [music]
>> Jazz hat like Laroche, black derbies and
denim Comme des Garçons bag for the
boosters.
Coco Rosie, codeine [music] tripping in
a hole with no heat. Grandmaster Flash
gave me a job. Cold star rich to room is
love. Meritocracy, [__] it, [__] and
squeeze. Tender-headed black boys
sleeping under the ginkgo tree dreaming
of a coming of the bull. Make [music]
trouble for you.
3D printing guns to gentrify public
school. This is Bucktown. All I lost was
my mustache. Rank and file they all cut
down. What now?
>> Should've killed me [music] when you had
the chance. Now it's out your hands. I
don't need an advance. I don't dance.
Her dog voice over the camera pans.
Everybody's a camera man. [music] It's
no use writing. Rest assured you're
wasting words. The world doesn't turn
anymore. Half burned out of the shadow
[music] never saw burning books to keep
warm.
>> Should've killed him when you had the
chance. Overseas under passes cut hand
shield matches fetinol dream catcher.
9-5 dream snatcher bleed you slow once
you captured. Say less it's tested. I
should've killed him when I had the
chance.
>> Back Packers back with weights and
measures. Coded language makes her
anxious. I can taste it. When chicken
heads come home to roost. No it's not
the same as you and Empress new groove.
Can't play it straight. Frank sipping
gold screw face. Who knows?
Like palm spray reparation. Pay more be
poor that's just basic. Ain't no
ambulance. Ain't no spaceship for no
[__] tonight.
>> Hell no. Hell no. Won't be no very
[music] special negro show tonight.
>> Went to sleep in retreat and woke up
defeated. Every man for himself that's
the eating. God [music] side with the
winners. The thief next to Jesus. I
wanted to be better than my father but
history just repeated. Mystery God but
y'all still looking for a reason. Broken
man playing out this string. It's
football season. December in Cleveland.
Lining up and then my heart already
beating. Narrow cot that I slept on raw.
No mirror, I already know.
>> [music]
>> Killers on the stairs, man in the hole.
I'M THROUGH RUNNING.
YEAH.
>> [cheering and applause]
>> I'M ELUCID.
>> [applause]
>> THIS IS BILLY WOODS. WE ARE Armand
Hammer.
Yeah, yeah. [music]
Yeah, yeah.
>> [music]
>> Uh, of course she grabs hair that grows
towards heaven. Pressure in possession,
melted. Black hole she fell in, well
then. Every other year I'm shedding.
[music] Core element, delicate.
Contained the Cheerios in cabinets.
Black China, no embellishment. Nobody
really getting [music] over it, so
relative. Ahead of my time since '99.
Discipline development. Jealous God,
well at odds. [music] Spilling out
shellac and fella. Don't sell daddy no
whiskey. Miss me not. My cologne been
autumn's rot. From locks to socks
[music] and fella been. Babylon medicine
wretch. Projected head first, innocent
step. Fell all out the loop, still
feeling woozy. Been the moodiest.
[music] Miss me with your corny news.
Many moons pinned where I've been and
where I've moved. My room grew peculiar
and wild. Style cast [music] shadow like
sundial to the
>> We had fun on that Super Nintendo.
[music]
>> Sunday service, blue church out the
window.
>> We was drunk, finger guns to our
temples.
>> We had fun on [music] that Super
Nintendo. [singing]
>> Towel the door, blue trees out the
window.
>> Yo, we was [music] drunk, finger guns to
our temples.
>> We had a time, don't let them say
different. We was drunk and [music] high
watching Intervention. We was just happy
to be outside when all peoples is in
prisons of all types.
>> We was just living. It's easy [singing]
now to talk [music] about wrong and
right. We was just living. It's easy now
that you know the price. We was just
running and ripping hands full of life.
Hard to explain to you. Never mind all
that. Just put the money in [music] the
hat. Rewind my old raps. Wondering where
that brother's at. Mom's half dead,
[music] still sharp, but starting to
forget. Repeating herself, retracing our
steps. She used to be up late pacing.
Now she sleep [music] like the dead. I
passed out on the couch dreams like
lads.
>> We had fun on that [music] Super
Nintendo.
>> Out the door, blew trees out the window.
>> Yo, we was done. Figured [music] guns to
our temple.
>> We had fun on that Super Nintendo.
>> Sunday services, blew [music] church out
the window. [singing]
>> We was done. Figured guns to our temple.
>> We had fun on that Super Nintendo.
>> Church [music] out the window. We had
fun on that Super Nintendo.
>> Hey.
>> We had [singing] fun.
We had fun [music] on that.
>> [music]
[cheering]
[applause]
>> Uh Kenny Siegal.
That's what we doing next?
>> Yep.
>> Okay.
>> And we got Ryan
>> Ryan on the guitar, Ryan Crosby.
>> [cheering]
[music and applause]
[music]
>> March through the orchestra pit. The rib
city [singing] all scared. You hope the
CDS don't stick [music] bend over those
sick. Too scared to write the book. Took
it, put it in the hook of a song. Nobody
listened to it. Looks like I wasn't
wrong. Hit it where they won't look
looking like Sodom. Looking at Taiwan
like, "Look, they shook. Let's get it
on."
>> [music]
>> Shots wiz, my [singing] depression was
all gone. Emotional lifted, please use
the proper form. Bend at the knees, roll
half a Guam. Lost no sleep over the
failure [music] white form. What goes
come back around, so when it came for
me, I wasn't alarmed.
>> [music]
>> Get fished out the hole like Sodom.
Tough guys won't go live, get [music]
get found. Uh-uh.
An object in motion stays in motion.
[music] I wait to the sea calm. Slaves
like Hammy Brown, ships was yay long.
It's too late for qualms with the hammer
in the palm. You was slayed in the
hammer, you do what it wants. Take the
good [music] with the bad. Fly trees in
the cheap blunt. [__] put up a good
front, but I can see the zipper. Before
he took a hit, I watched a negro [music]
shiver. That's that Bill Withers.
Neighbors had the nerve to say you can't
take it [singing] with you.
[__] with I want with any of this [__]
Dummies. [music]
SpongeBob, the whole operation
underwater. It's only one God what we
cried and tore aboard. The bombs is on
us, the forms is on [music] us. Came
back to God like, "Motherfucker, you
promised."
You promised.
SpongeBob, the whole operation [singing]
underwater. It's only one [music] God
what they cried and tore aboard. The
bombs is on us, the forms is on us.
>> [music]
>> Came back to God like, "Motherfucker,
you promised."
You promised.
>> [music]
>> I get five out of phone cards at the
corner store. It's hot. Gang [music]
gang crowded in the door. Slip past.
Don't you bump nobody. The body control
was godly. It's just a hobby picked up
in the [singing and music] lobby. It's
that negro karate. Summers, dirt bikes,
and Kawasakis numbers [music] Fibonacci.
Overseas connection choppy. [singing]
She's getting worse. Your sister talked
to the nurse. Everybody [music] at
church. Everybody wants to know if you
coming but they won't [singing] say the
words. Your days feel rehearsed. Nights
come back [music] in short bursts. At
the bodega baseheads lurk hopping. Put
the foot young and slow in his [music]
work. Got my every call car but I
[singing] keep it lotto first. I don't
want [music] to see him put her in the
dirt. I can't go there with nothing but
my shirt. Explosions outside bombs
bursting in the sky. Streets, sidewalks,
it's the 3rd of [__] July.
>> [music]
>> SpongeBob the whole operation
underwater. It's only one God what we
cried and tore aboard. [music] The bombs
rained on us. The bombs rained on us.
Came back to God like [__] you
promised. [music]
You promised.
SpongeBob the whole operation
underwater. It's only [music] one God
what we preached and tore aboard.
[singing] Those bombs was on us. Those
bombs was on us. [music] Came back to
God like [__] you promised.
You promised.
>> [music]
>> You have $10.22
remaining [music] in your account.
Please enter the telephone number you
wish to dial now or press *0 to recharge
and hear the main menu [music] options.
>> [music]
>> WOO!
>> [cheering]
[applause]
[cheering]
>> WOO!
>> [applause]
[cheering]
[applause]
>> NOW YOU GET TO HEAL THE PEOPLE. SO, YOU
KNOW, YOU know how it goes. That's the
That's the dynamic.
>> [music]
>> They have made this star unsafe. [music]
>> This age primitive.
Though your mind is somewhere else.
>> [music]
>> Your ass ain't.
Your ass
ain't.
>> [music]
[music]
>> I said
piece of the child actor.
Hey y'all.
I said heart to heart.
What earth is hollow, sent the heart.
Following my [music] arc, you should
park where you start. I'm a dancer in
the dark, running tangents off the mark.
If you're seeking understanding, [music]
you should jam this where you are. I
abandoned being starved through plans
that weren't for tomorrow. Two hands to
paint the walks beyond us. [music]
Needings [singing] and wantings, no
fault of conscience. Secrets and
hauntings. Seasons of harvest, I'm
carrier. [singing]
Ascariot slit her the valley. I fear not
in the shadow. Peppermint and aloe.
Poured upon the crown, still shining.
South Jamaica way is Strong Island.
[singing] JFK sonic boom. All the places
I've been. I've been.
Spelling.
Oh, just got to heaven I can't sit out.
Just got to heaven [singing and music]
and I can't sit out. Just got to heaven
and I can't sit [music] out. Just got to
heaven and I can't sit out.
Earth [music] and sky and the cloud
between. 10,000 goodbyes, the hour's
fleeting. Let the dollars circulate,
[singing and music] I never vowed
allegiance. When I [__] you, it was
worth the weight, the rhyme [singing]
and reason. My head is round, so I can
change my mind. Been your mama's
favorite since about '88, '89. Thick
wave rocker lot of stash pocket. Free
lunch [music] summer, razor flat top.
CP5 and Chevy Blazer. Gold bread, too
much work. Walk away first, might as
well go ahead. Late triple welfare.
Built for self, can't [music] get off
the web. The bugs were in the bed, I
cracked a couple eggs. Love sucks, but
illin' other ways. [singing and music]
Spaces to be taken.
Just got [music] to heaven and I can't
sit out.
Just got to heaven and I can't [singing]
sit out. Just got to heaven [music] and
I can't sit out.
Just got to heaven and I can't sit out.
Just got [music and singing] to heaven
and I can't sit out.
Just got to heaven and I can't [music]
sit out. Just got to heaven and I
and I
I've been I've been spelling.
Spelling.
Just got to heaven and I can't sit out.
Just got to heaven and I
>> [music]
[applause]
>> 1
>> [music]
[music]
>> Location, location, [music] location,
location, I won't be located. [singing]
Location, location, location, location,
[music] I won't be located.
Location.
>> [music]
>> Someone else's dream.
Out of reach. Fire keeper for this life
it leaves. [music and singing]
Why are we? Why are we?
Guide [singing and music] my feet. I'm
entirely
someone else's dream.
Someone else's dream.
Out of reach.
Fire keeper [music] for this life it
leaves.
Why are we?
Why are we? [music and singing]
Guide my feet. I'm entirely
someone else's [music] dream.
Someone else's dream.
No wealth received. My belts recede and
expand. [music and singing] Say what I
said, it doesn't need a response. Taking
space when I want.
To the east by land, scene cut. Lead
with my hands as light advances. Exposed
beams. Good bones still gabbling.
The night's on, [music] pouring deep.
Texting three black hearts on the
landing strip. Fear of abandonment not
my bag, no need [music] to handle it.
Fiddle like a man and [__] Whatever
[singing] that spells. Psychic faults
and damages.
>> [music]
>> Leading with my hammer. Bloody gauze
[singing] and bandages. Lining the
canvases. texture coarse, quicker sand
or sift, [music]
I grew hoarse standing in gift, my black
ass to kiss, a standard [singing] win.
The level's been leveled.
>> The level [music] in the forest, face
painted, fingertips [singing] black with
charcoal. I waited and waited. Anything
I gave, [music] I weighted. Same as I
got, anything I caught, I killed it, I
ate it. I can't be located.
>> I can't be located. Face pixelated.
[music] Face pressed to pavement, knee
and my [singing] spine the crowd
undulated, phones raised in their own
faces. She's under me, eyes search my
face. Baby girl, just face [music] it.
I'd rather carry myself, I already
[singing] paid the freightage. I played
face in the faces, Miles [music] Davis.
I slept in the basement. Walls cried,
jotted on the paper. I can't be located.
>> [music]
>> be located.
>> Shadows split between leaves, splotches
of green, mosses cling to trees. I'm
under the pain. You can't come in here
with me. [singing] You can't come in
here with me. Can't come in here, you'll
see. I can't be located. [music]
>> I can't be located.
Location, location, location, [music]
location, I won't be located.
Location, location, location, location,
I won't be located. [music]
I won't be located.
Location, location, [music] location,
location, I won't be located.
>> Yo, yo, yo.
Human Error Club on the beat
playing [music] their own material.
One of my favorite Human Error [music]
joints.
Give it up for the [__] band.
Yeah.
>> [music]
[music]
[cheering and applause]
[applause]
>> We played a lot of uh album closes
already in this set, but it was
it when it came down to it, there was
really only one joint we could close the
whole record with. Shout out to Uncle
Al.
Let's go.
>> [screaming]
>> I don't want [singing] to lose control,
but I can't cramp my space to grow.
Comfort's tall, but gets us through. I
got so much left to undo it. I don't
want to lose control, but I can't cramp
my space to grow.
Comfort's [music]
tall, but gets us through. I got so much
left to undo, okay. Host is [music]
hostile, steals what's true. I got so
much left to undo it. Never [singing]
ends like [music] light I've been dying.
Cold for wind's eye. Beyond men die.
Walk through doors, my name's on
[singing and music] no list. Change is
not for sure a slow shift. Glacial
tides, [music and singing] the tides are
rising.
Got to high dive in alive
where I really came in on a cyclone. The
disciple [music] scribed the scroll with
my eyes closed. Knights thrown,
[singing]
black handle, blowing smoke, slapping
comb gods. There I go. There I go.
Flexibility, [music]
reciprocity, [singing]
what I need but sure not all I need.
That's impossible.
I don't want to lose control but I can't
cramp my space to grow up.
Comfort stubborn
gets us through. I got so much left to
undo it.
I [singing and music] don't want to lose
control but I can't cramp my space to
[music] grow up.
Comfort stubborn gets us through.
[singing]
I got so much left to undo it.
>> [singing]
>> She said okay to save face but she never
forgave.
>> It's only so many [music] ways you can
say grace and truth.
>> She'd rather cry at my grave. All black
regalia, [music] we back not speaking.
Back behind bougainvillea, you can't
>> [singing]
>> Marginally busy with symbols and
equations. The science too simple to
calculate it. Payment postdated. The
payment gave way to a thicket of thorns
where the body laid naked is the day I
was born. Rocked teeth in a necklace,
gold blood from a horn.
Ruby wolf facing mega head disheveled
and torn. She left what was left in the
ditch.
>> [singing]
>> She dreaming of sex. She finished on top
and howled in the crook of my neck. She
dragged the bones home and built a bed.
She dragged rosé out the scabbard held
it gentle as my living hand.
>> [music]
>> I don't want to
lose control, [singing] but
I can't grab
space to grow.
Comfort zone, but gets us through.
I got so [music] much left to undo.
I don't want [singing]
to
lose [music] control, but
I can't grab my space to grow.
>> [music]
>> Shout out Willie Green, all our
Backwoods family.
>> yeah.
>> [cheering and applause]
[applause]
[cheering]
>> Thanks for watching. Support for NPR
Music comes from Rivian, makers of
all-electric adventure vehicles,
including the R1S three-row SUV. More at
rivian.com.
>> A quick update before you go. We're
doing another Tiny Desk giveaway. Enter
by September 12th, 2026, and you and a
friend could win a free trip to DC to
see a Tiny Desk concert live in person.
You even get to choose which upcoming
show you want to see, and it's
completely free to enter. Just go to
npr.org/tinydeskgiveaway.
Entering is completely free, but you can
get more entries by snagging some
limited edition Tiny Desk merch or by
making a special donation to the NPR
network. Learn more and enter today at
npr.org/tinydeskgiveaway.
Okay.